Austin Wiley

5974 S. Fairfield St., Littleton, Colorado 80120 — 303.905.7293 — austinwiley84@gmail.com

Objective

Skilled full stack developer with experience in web server development and deployment. Dedicated to improving the development methods used to create new software programs. Thanks to years of working in cross-functional teams and running my own business, I'm great at coming up with solutions, no matter what you throw at me.

Education

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP APRIL 2019 — UNIVERSITY OF DENVER, DENVER, CO

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications.

Skills & Abilities

· Node.js

 \cdot Express.js

· React / React Native

· JavaScript (ES6)

· Auth0 (Authentication)

· jQuery

· HTML5 / CSS3

· Bulma

Bootstrap

Materialize

Handlebars.js

Moment.js

· NPM

· Git

· Bash

· Heroku

· Docker

 \cdot AWS

Python

· MongoDB

· Mongoose-ODM

· MySQL

· Sequelize-ORM

Firebase

Applications Built

GETTING THERE GUIDE APP

Worked as part of a small consulting team to develop a React Native (iOS and Android) mobile app for specialized transportation services in the Denver metro area serving persons with disabilities and the elderly.

IOT (INTERNET OF THINGS) TEMPERATURE CONTROLLER

Designed, developed, installed and maintained a remote temperature controller for monitoring and setting brewing equipment temperatures.

HYPERLOCAL

Collaborated with a small team to create a backend API as well as front end user authentication and UI components for a web-based app. The app, Hyperlocal, is a forum for fostering real world connections through shared interests while stimulating community interaction.

BEERKAN

Designed and built full stack solution for the professional brewer and avid homebrewer that works like a Kanban Board for tracking beer throughout the brewing process. BeerKan is a digital Brew log allowing the user to track each batch of beer from raw ingredients to keg. The web-based software allows the brewer to be more efficient, brew more beer and archive all brew logs.

Experience

DEVELOPER — DIGITAL PIXEL (LITTLETON, CO) NOVEMBER 2019 ~ PRESENT

- · Develops and builds both React and React-native applications based on client requirements.
- Performs coding, debugging, testing and troubleshooting throughout the application development process utilizing Jira and Bitbucket for project management.
- · Collaborates on technical code solutions prior to implementation.
- · Maintains existing WordPress websites.

TECHNICAL SUPPORT SPECIALIST — FOUR WINDS INTERACTIVE (DENVER, CO) JUNE 2019 ~ PRESENT

- · Supports clients with home-grown software.
- · Remotely performs network troubleshooting on client systems.
- · Debugs software on Android and Web OS.
- · Audits Windows desktop environments including review of system logs.
- · Authors batch scripts to automate tasks.
- Performs changes using RegEdit, edited Group Policies including set up of file sharing, updated drivers, applied software patches and completed upgrades.
- · Managed client information using Salesforce.

OWNER FOUNDER, MANAGER AND SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR SPANGALANG BREWERY (DENVER, CO) FEBRUARY 2015 ~JUNE 2019

- · Co-Founded and Operated a successful craft brewery.
- · Created world class beers, some of which won the GABF Gold medal and World Beer Cup awards.
- Duties included management of daily operations, human resources and systems administration of digital assets.
- · Architected a set of web-based tools for managing brewhouse operations to optimize profitability.
- · Researched local and federal laws and regulations, obtained necessary permits and licenses.
- · Acted as lead project manager between equipment engineers, architects, contractors, and local government.

HEAD BREWER — DENVER BEER CO (DENVER, CO) FEBRUARY 2014 ~FEBRUARY 2015

- · Managed Brew house operations and staff during a time of major growth.
- Maintained Brewery computers including system updates, hardware setup and troubleshooting for all windows machines.
- Developed and Brewed beer which became a major part of the company's portfolio, these beers are now nationally recognized and have received awards and medals.

LEAD BREWER — GREAT DIVIDE BREWING CO (DENVER, CO) APRIL 2007 ~ FEBRUARY 2014

- · Researched and created recipes for award winning beers.
- · Optimized team management and staff training.
- Improved equipment acquisition lifecycles and established production standards playing a major role in helping the company increase sales volume during a time of rapid growth.

References

References are available upon request.

Supporting Links

- Github: https://github.com/AustinWiley
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/austin-wiley-86868416b/
- Portfolio: https://austinwiley.dev/